Salar Houshvand

□ 2528644195 • ☑ salarhoushvand@gmail.com

salarhoushvand.github.io/myresume • in salar-houshvand • SalarHoushvand

Web Developer with experience in academic projects. Knowledgeable in user interface, back-end, graphc design and database. My primary skill is in web application developmet using Python, Java Script, HTML and CSS.

Experience

East Carolina University (NSF RED:PPSE PROJECT)

Greenville, NC

Web Developer May 2019 - Dec 2020

- Designed and implemented the user interface of the website using React.js, CSS and HTML.
- Developed algorithms to automatically generate questions for different topics in discrete mathematics.
- Designed logo, depicts and clip arts using Adobe Photoshop.

East Carolina University

Greenville, NC

Graduate Assistant

January 2019 - Dec 2020

- Assisted faculty in the development of high-quality graphs for illustrating complex technical concepts using Lucidchart, GeoGebra, Latex, and Excel.
- Strong data analysis skills are shown in developing data for the Computer department's external evaluation report; submits
 all concise reports on time.
- Mentored new colleagues by conducting recitation sessions and leading lab classes for algorithmic problem solving (CSCI1010).

Sky Design

Tabriz, Iran

Graphic Designer

November 2013 - February 2015

- Conceptualized and developed graphics products for product illustrations, company logos and online website projects using Adobe Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, among others.
- Coordinated, created and scheduled content, designs and periodic updates to the company website.

Projects

RESTful API for Discrete Math GitHub

- Developed a RESTful API using Python's Flask library to generate unlimited number of questions and their answers on selected topics in discrete math.
- The goal was to help students practice their mathematical skills for different questions.
- OCR tool for Telugu GitHub
 - Developed an OCR tool using Python to convert image file to text.
 - By using this application unlimited number of handwritten documents in Telugu language can be converted to text in making corpus for future projects.
- Input form template GitHub
 - Responsive input form designed with HTML, CSS. Using Python as back-end. Deployed throuth Heroku and stores image files using Amazon AWS.
- o **Input form template** GitHub
 - Responsive input form designed with HTML, CSS. Using Python as back-end. Deployed throuth Heroku and stores image files using Amazon AWS.

Education

Master of Science (M.S.), Software Engineering

East Carolina University

Greenville, NC

2019 - 2020

Skills

- Programming Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript
- Web Development: HTML, CSS, SQL, React, AWS, Darabase
- o Other: Version Control, Scrum, MS Office Suit, Adobe Suit.
- Languages: English(Professional Proficiency), Turkish (Native), Persian(Native), French(Elementary Proficiency)